Matthew Auld

474 Lawson Ave, Ottawa (613) 600-4943 matthew@matthewauld.ca www.matthewauld.ca

Recently returned to school to pursue my passion for Computer Science, I have five years of experience in nonprofit marketing at the Canadian Red Cross. I have proven myself to be an independent, critical thinker who can work under pressure. I am looking for an opportunity to apply myself and learn from professionals working in the field.

Skills

- Languages: Python, Java, SQL, HTML, C++
- Databases: MySQL, Microsoft SQL Server
- Operating Systems: OSX, Windows, Linux (including Ubuntu Server)
- Worked with vendors and internal teams on large, data-driven projects
- Analysis using SSMS, SSRS, Pointillist, Python Pandas
- Lifelong tinkerer, maker and explorer

Education

2017-PRESENT (IN PROGRESS)

B.Sc Computer Science (Honours)/ Carleton University

- Specializing in Cyber Security and Software Engineering
- Dean's List 2017-2018
- Murdoch Maxwell MacOdrum Scholarship 2018-2019

SEPT 2006 - JUNE 2011

B.A Political Science (Honours) / University of Guelph

- Completed a degree in Political Science, specializing in Public Administration and Law
- Took upper year classes in economics, including international political economics and labour economics

Experience

MAR 2018 - PRESENT (PART TIME), SUMMER 2018 (FULL TIME)

Data Analyst / Canadian Red Cross

- Developed and maintained internal migration and data cleanup documentation.
- Developed scripts to extract, analyze and compile translation tables from Raiser's Edge using SQL and Python
- Assisted in designing, planning and managing data migration process
- Troubleshot conversion issues with the Blackbaud Data Conversion Specialist
- Monitored data consistency, diagnose issues and proactively develop methodologies to improve data quality

 Attended training on Blackbaud Data Warehouse construction and reporting, and CRM data output and reporting

•

JULY 2016 - AUGUST 2017 (FULL TIME), SEPTEMBER 2017 - PRESENT (PART TIME)

National Stewardship Coordinator / Canadian Red Cross

- Improved reporting and data analysis tools, working to combine data from online and offline sources to analyze effectiveness of loyalty and retention strategies
- Using Python Pandas, SQL and Pointillist software, preformed data analysis to identify opportunities to improve donor retention
- Worked with vendors and internal partners to automate stewardship marketing processes, including welcome emails, surveys, and the fast identification of problems.
- Working with public affairs, program, data, translation and design teams, I managed the
 development and of stewardship material for all Canadian Red Cross stakeholders and donors,
 including major reports for the 2016 Alberta Fires and 2017 BC Floods
- Implemented ongoing surveys to gather data from donors and staff to identify areas of improvement and ensure quality control

MAY 2013 - JULY 2016

Community Engagement Associate / Canadian Red Cross

- Rewrote the Community Fundraising Handbook to be more donor friendly and better align with Canadian Red Cross brand
- Helped to develop, update, and report on budget and business plan
- Responsible for building and managing relationships with community partners across the province, including major corporations, community groups, and government agencies
- Ensured community fundraisers met all legal requirements, design standards, and approved communications for events
- Created and executed media events to promote the domestic Disaster Management work of the Canadian Red Cross
- Managed Community relations and hundreds of Community Fundraisers during the Nepal Earthquake, Fort McMurray Fires, and Syrian Refugee Crisis appeals
- Built financial reporting and stewardship tracking tools with Raiser's Edge, Excel, and Access

Volunteer Experience

Disaster Management Responder and Logistics Lead / Canadian Red Cross

JULY 2016 - DEC 2018

- Met with all logistics team members to assess their skills and availability
- Delegated regular maintenance and stocking tasks to other volunteers
- Developed logistics database to track assets and inventory levels
- Standardized warehousing procedures and trained volunteers and implement systems
- Supported the spring flood evacuations in 2014 and 2015, Syrian Response as well as a number of major fires

- Working with volunteers, renewed and expanded PDA supplier agreements and built a database to manage the relationships to ensure they are renewed in a timely fashion
- Sat on the ERMS working group, developing SOPs for using the ERMS for level 2 responses in Ottawa-Lanark-Renfew
- Deployed to Fort McMurray in June 2016 as Logistics Manager stationed there. Was tasked with implementing all procurement, inventory and asset tracking for the response.

First Aid Services Team Responder / Canadian Red Cross

JUN 2013 - AUGUST 2016

- Member of FAST, providing first aid services during community events
- Certified in First Aid